<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>


<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title type="text">Le Blog</title>
    <subtitle type="html">MemE is a powerful and highly customizable GoHugo theme for personal blogs.</subtitle>
    <updated>2020-07-08T13:04:03&#43;03:00</updated>
    <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom&#43;xml" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/atom.xml" />
    <author>
            <name>yogi</name>
            <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
            
                <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
    <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights>
    <generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.73.0">Hugo</generator>
        <entry>
            <title type="text">When Snow Gets in Your Shoes</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/when-snow-gets-in-your-shoes/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/when-snow-gets-in-your-shoes/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:03&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2019-01-21T11:41:31&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">So I haven’t been here since November 24 of last year and this is supposed to be a daily blog. I have my excuse ready – I’ve moved to a new country!</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I haven’t been here since November 24 of last year and this is supposed to be a daily blog. I have my excuse ready – I’ve moved to a new country! So on New Year’s day 2019, I hopped on a flight from Bangalore and moved to Helsinki. On hindsight, I could have picked a more favorable month to move. January is really brutal here, there’s snow everywhere and it is really annoying when it gets in your shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like Finland though. People are nice and polite. Mostly they keep it to themselves and don’t go around throwing fake plesantaries (ahem… SoCal). And there’s an ever-present palpable silence everywhere, which I absolutely love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don’t get to meet the Sun very often. Even on those rare non-overcast days, Sun only shines between 9 in the morning to 4 in the evening. It’s lazier than a DMV employee, right? Also, the temperatures has been consistently subzero ever since I moved here. So there’s not much I can do when I am outside besides walking as quickly as possible to the nearest temperate controlled room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good times!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">The Bet</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/the-bet/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/the-bet/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:21&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-22T11:40:16&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">I wouldn’t go as far as to call myself a voracious book reader, but I have read enough over the years to develop a taste for fine books, like a connoisseur.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t go as far as to call myself a voracious book reader, but I have read enough over the years to develop a taste for fine books, like a connoisseur. I can imbibe the stellar works of the Fitzgeralds and the Steinbecks with immeasurable glee while astutely dodging the mediocrity of the Dan Browns and Chetan Bhagats. These days I read pretty much indiscriminately from all genres and I value the knowledge I get from these books. But I wasn’t always like this, I used to loathe reading anything longer than a few 10s of pages. The first book I ever read was an illustrated and abridged version of Oliver Twist, I liked it, but wouldn’t have pulled through without the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was this short story called “The Bet” as a part of my middle school’s English curriculum, which had a profound impact on my reading habits. The Bet is between two men about whether the death penalty or life imprisonment is a harsher sentence. The richer of the dudes (of course, a banker) agreed offer two million bucks if the other guy stays in prison for 15 years. The prisoner is allowed to read any number of books as long as he agrees to never leave the room or meet other people. Towards the end of 15 years, sensing that the prisoner has almost pulled off the wager, the banker tries to kill off the prisoner when he comes across a note left by the prisoner announcing his renouncement of the prize money. The prisoner ascribed his decision to the immense pleasure and wisdom he acquired through those books. He writes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is true I have not seen the earth nor men, but in your books I have drunk fragrant wine, I have sung songs, I have hunted stags and wild boars in the forests, have loved women … Beauties as ethereal as clouds, created by the magic of your poets and geniuses, have visited me at night, and have whispered in my ears wonderful tales that have set my brain in a whirl. In your books I have climbed to the peaks of Elburz and Mont Blanc, and from there I have seen the sun rise and have watched it at evening flood the sky, the ocean, and the mountain-tops with gold and crimson.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story had a profound impact on me because I was in a way locked in a prison myself when I first read it. I read this during my final exams and exam time was always a curfew in my house, with no television or play time and I used to religiously count down to the last day of the exam. I remember vowing to give this reading business another shot once the exams were done. I started off easy with an Agatha Christie novel about Egyptian pharaohs. The suspense provided the motivation to complete the book and since Ms. Christie is an excellent writer, I was transcended to Egypt during an era of embitterment between Mr and Mrs Pharaoh. Having read just over 100 books (not much I know, but am not bragging :D), I have had variegated experiences like the philosophy of existentialism, a war camaraderie, a sliver of hope amidst post-apocalyptic despondence, the outlandish awe of a window seat on a space shuttle, to name a few. I will be eternally indebted to this short story for setting me on this path of literary bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">Like Rocky, but the opposite</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/like-rocky-but-the-opposite/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/like-rocky-but-the-opposite/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:27&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-21T11:38:05&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">I’ve never had much of an upper body strength. I can do 3/4th of a pull up and maybe 3.5 pushups before I get the wind knocked out of me, I then slyly duck down to catch my breath pretending to tie (actually, untie then tie) my shoelaces.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve never had much of an upper body strength. I can do 3/4th of a pull up and maybe 3.5 pushups before I get the wind knocked out of me, I then slyly duck down to catch my breath pretending to tie (actually, untie then tie) my shoelaces. I never understood why gym trainers always ask you start with these insane body-weight exercises before you’re allowed to touch weights. Gym dumbbells for example, start at 5 lbs with 0.5 lbs increments while my generously rotund body weighs 165 lbs, shouldn’t we be doing body-weight exercises after we lose weight at the gym?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My legs however, are in a much better shape. They are like two pistons of an internal combustion engine, relentlessly converting sambar into forward propulsion at a rate between 3-6 mph. So to stop being fat, I run. I have this theory that pull-ups will be much easier after I lose a few. In my younger days, running was never a problem – be it on a treadmill or out in the open, I had always managed to burn a few hundred calories every session without any fuss. The muscles used to be sore for a day or two, but eventually I always got into a nice running rhythm. These days, as am nearing the end of my physical heydays, the sore muscles tend to outstay their welcome by a few days, sometimes weeks. This is a major problem because currently I am in one of the worst shapes that I’ve ever been in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been running quite consistently for the past couple of weeks, one can only bear through a finite number of “oh man you’ve put on weight, haven’t you” comments from soulless dweebs (#shakeitoff). Anyway, it has been really hard. I have driveled and crawled through the uphill roads of Ooty during the first week, sometimes it felt like my ankles were about to fall apart after each run. Now after 2 weeks, it feels like my ankles have finally upgraded themselves to support my enormous weight. Along the way, I had to change my diet (more veggies and less carbs), my shoes and mindset. Now I know how Rocky felt at the end of the movie. Wait I never saw that movie, he won right? I just googled it, he lost. I feel the opposite of what rocky felt. There.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">Writer’s Block</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/writers-block/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/writers-block/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:38&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-15T11:37:12&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">Oh my, oh my. How naive was I, to assume that I’d have anything worthwhile to tell you everyday. Nope, I have nothing.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh my, oh my. How naive was I, to assume that I’d have anything worthwhile to tell you everyday. Nope, I have nothing. Brick friggin’ wall. (Allow me to take the liberty of calling myself a writer) So this is what writer’s block feels like. It’s 10pm everyday by the time I get to sit and write something. I have other chores to complete, don’t I? The 2 hour deadline until midnight to write something interesting drives me crazy. I have so many drafts open with unfinished blogs, I gave up on them because they suck. I can write about the books I read, but I take an average of 3-4 days to complete one. Majority of those books are just meh, and provide nothing useful to write about. Maybe I can write about the news, but why would you come here to read about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never was at a lose for words when I write my journal. But we’re not that close, I can’t tell you personal stuff. Okay, I’ll tell you one personal stuff; I think I’m going bald (although others assure me I’m not), so I spent some time today researching hair transplantation and might have to start saving for it soon. I haven’t the slightest idea why planting hair nodes on a bald head should cost so much. Maybe there’s a monopoly there. Someone should file an anti-trust lawsuit against them. But this is not interesting, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">How to Tell a Story</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-tell-a-story/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-tell-a-story/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:29&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-12T11:36:11&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">I noticed this with stand-up comedy when I hear a great joke from, say, Bill Burr or John Mulaney and want to share it with someone.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I noticed this with stand-up comedy when I hear a great joke from, say, Bill Burr or John Mulaney and want to share it with someone. I almost always butcher the delivery and the joke doesn’t seem that funny anymore. I try real hard to mimic the exact delivery of the joke, the pauses, emphasis on the right syllables, everything to the book, but the joke still doesn’t have the same effect. That’s when I give up and just share a YouTube link, then the joke always draws out a laugh from my friend. Practice and experience. I think that’s what I was lacking, and probably also the talent for stand-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, writing is similar. As an aspiring story-teller I often try to observe the technique a writer uses in a book. Some great writers can take an ordinary event and pen it down so well by adding all the glitz and glamour. When you write down all the exact details of the event, you write an encyclopedia, but when you make the reader feel like he is walking in the same city and breathing the same air as the characters, you write a great novel. Practice, experience and talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finished reading The Things They Carried by Tim O’Brien and looked back at all the quotes I had highlighted through the book, I realized that this book was about storytelling. Sure, this was about the Vietnam War, written by the author who was actually in that war. It was about the emotions that the soldiers felt, how they were just pushed onto the battlefield underprepared and unmotivated. It was about the friends lost during those years and how they coped with the years after war. But underneath all this, it was a confession (as one of the reviewers astutely observed), it was a way for the author to get things off his chest. This book was a collection of anecdotes, like those you’d hear from an old war veteran sitting alone in a subway cart, if you took the time to chat him up. The stories were extraordinary, so extraordinary that even a mediocre writer could have captivated the reader with it. O’Brien never fully focused on the nitty-gritty, because that’s not what matters. These stories had a purpose, not to describe the gore and chaos of the Vietnam War, but to give identity to the soldiers who fought in it. In one chapter, the author described how everyone was indistinguishable from each other when they had mud smeared across their face, I think this book was about washing off that mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave you with some of these highlights from the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s what stories are for. Stories are for joining the past to the future. Stories are for those late hours in the night when you can’t remember how you got from where you were to where you are. Stories are for eternity, when memory is erased, when there is nothing to remember except the story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A true war story is never moral. It does not instruct, nor encourage virtue, nor suggest models of proper human behavior, nor restrain men from doing the things men have always done. If a story seems moral, do not believe it. If at the end of a war story you feel uplifted, or if you feel that some small bit of rectitude has been salvaged from the larger waste, then you have been made the victim of a very old and terrible lie.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“By telling stories, you objectify your own experience. You separate it from yourself. You pin down certain truths. You make up others.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The thing about a story is that you dream it as you tell it, hoping that others might then dream along with you, and in this way memory and imagination and language combine to make spirits in the head.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">Oh No! Silence</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/oh-no-silence/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/oh-no-silence/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:25&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-10T11:35:04&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">People often talk about their fear of speaking to strangers, or even to friends sometimes. How many times have we sat there in the awkward silence for what feels like an eternity, when you run out of any topics to discuss.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;People often talk about their fear of speaking to strangers, or even to friends sometimes. How many times have we sat there in the awkward silence for what feels like an eternity, when you run out of any topics to discuss. I have deliberately worked on my conversation skills as an adult and can keep up a fairly interesting conversation with people. People usually open up when you talk about their work or their city (especially New Yorkers) or if you have nothing else, about the weather (especially with Americans). But what is so uncomfortable about the silence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silences always end up being awkward, its when the mobile phones pop out, followed by the mindless scrolls through some social media website. My mind usually goes into a panic mode when confronted with prolonged calm, that’s when a poorly constructed joke or a gossip about an old friend is brought out. Why can’t two people just sit there and not talk and just ruminate their thoughts? It is possible that a conversation with periodic pauses could be profound, something that actually could leave a lasting impression on the other person. President Obama’s speeches used to have so many pauses, and it made you feel like he is trying to take the effort to say the right things, that he is not just winging it. He made you feel special. Won’t it be nice to make your interlocutor (okay I admit, I googled that word) feel that way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck, whoever is going to end up having coffee with me next 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">Diwali Causes Cancer</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/diwali-causes-cancer/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/diwali-causes-cancer/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:32&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-06T11:34:31&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">I love Diwali as much as the next guy, but I am done with this fireworks BS. I don’t know why sane people still insist on lighting fireworks during Diwali.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love Diwali as much as the next guy, but I am done with this fireworks BS. I don’t know why sane people still insist on lighting fireworks during Diwali. The toll this has on the environment is obvious. One would expect that during the age of PS4 and fortnite, it would be easier to get kids off of fireworks. As I drove through the city today, I could see the heavy metallic smoke emitted from these fireworks hover over the whole city. I saw poor street dogs running amok everywhere because they were so confused about all this sudden noise. Hope this stops soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">The Great Gatsby</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/the-great-gatsby/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/the-great-gatsby/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:22&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-05T11:14:13&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">Don’t judge me, but I finished reading The Great Gatsby only last week. I know, I know, it’s a classic, but I never cared for stories about rich people and their extravagant parties and their first world problems.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Don’t judge me, but I finished reading The Great Gatsby only last week. I know, I know, it’s a classic, but I never cared for stories about rich people and their extravagant parties and their first world problems. This year however, I have been covering a lot of classic novels and decided to give this a try. I was hooked from the very first sentence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In my younger and more vulnerable years my father gave me some advice that I’ve been turning over in my mind ever since. ‘Whenever you feel like criticizing any one,’ he told me, ‘just remember that all the people in this world haven’t had the advantages that you’ve had.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this book about empathetic rich people? Now that I can withstand. It didn’t take me long to find out that F. Scott Fitzgerald is a magician when it comes to bringing forth some extraordinary metaphors. Fitzgerald is one of those authors whose books you read and wonder “I can never write like that”. Check out this sentence which basically says, “it got dark while she was talking to me”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For a moment the last sunshine fell with romantic affection upon her glowing face; her voice compelled me forward breathlessly as I listened—then the glow faded, each light deserting her with lingering regret like children leaving a pleasant street at dusk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I most certainly can never write like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the book is not just about rich people having parties. I see this novel (and found some other reviewers who thought the same) as pointing a giant mirror at the myth of the American Dream – “if you work hard and with honesty, you can buy a car and a TV with HBO and own a 40 year mortgage on a house”, or something like that. Basically, anyone can become rich and move to Beverly Hills if he wants to. It is the opposite of the aristocratic society in countries like Great Britain (or Harry Potter) where a commoner can never be a part of the elite, no matter how rich he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby was born a commoner, but worked hard (and had some favorable luck) to become rich. But no matter how big is mansion and how generous his parties, the other rich people always saw him with suspicion. And unlike the rich people who had “smashed up things and creatures and then retreated back into their money or their vast carelessness, or whatever it was that kept them together and let other people clean up the mess they had made”, Gatsby had to pay a heavy price for his mistake. So the book points out that the American Dream isn’t really true, the rich and the poor have different rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was definitely one of the best books I’ve read and Fitzgerald has become one of my favorite authors.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">Streaks</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/streaks/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/streaks/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:20&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-04T11:12:58&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">Life is pointless, right? You have a lifelong dream of achieving some goal, then what happens after you achieve it? Boredom. I once went on a jungle safari in Southern India searching for elephants.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Life is pointless, right? You have a lifelong dream of achieving some goal, then what happens after you achieve it? Boredom. I once went on a jungle safari in Southern India searching for elephants. I had never seen a wild elephant before and spent the whole evening driving around trying to spot one. It was tiring, but the expectation added a bit of fun. Finally, I spotted a tusker going to town on a branch of bamboo. I saw the elephant, the elephant saw me, and then the elephant continued chewing the bamboo branch nonchalantly. It was my first brush with existentialism. What was the point of spending the whole evening trying to spot this bamboo eater? It amounted to nothing and I should have just left him alone. Please don’t go on a safari, imagine someone pointing a camera at you while you devour a T-bone steak. I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the sole benefit of having goals is not gained by achieving them, it is gained during the process of achieving the goal. Driving around with the expectation of finding a majestic elephant was enthralling. Having a staring contest with a bored elephant, not so much. So I found this iOS app called Streaks, where you can set up to 12 habits that you want to develop. The app gives me a to-do list for everyday and keeps track of the streak count for each of those tasks. When you’re well into a streak for a certain task, you get this extra motivation to complete it (like how am trying to fill this blog post up with gibberish right now). Cultivating good habits is the stepping stone to achieving any goal, and that my friend, is the secret to happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now am really out of topics to write about. Maybe tomorrow I’ll write about writer’s block.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        <entry>
            <title type="text">Where to begin?</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/where-to-begin/" />
            <id>https://ykumards.github.io/blog/posts/where-to-begin/</id>
            <updated>2020-07-08T12:44:47&#43;03:00</updated>
            <published>2018-11-03T10:48:16&#43;03:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>yogi</name>
                    <uri>https://ykumards.github.io/</uri>
                    <email>ykumards.public@gmail.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">I firmly believed that people with uninteresting lives shouldn’t start a daily blog. What’s there to share? This belief kept me clear off having any blogging ambitions.</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I firmly believed that people with uninteresting lives shouldn’t start a daily blog. What’s there to share? This belief kept me clear off having any blogging ambitions. Besides the creative procrastination and occasional bouts of coding, my life is fairly uneventful for 99/100 days (once every 3 months I attempt to run for 3 miles and nearly get a heart attack).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I realized that like any person nearing his mid-life crisis danger zone, I need some form of creative outlet. Guitar strings hurt my fingers too much and I couldn’t draw you a discernible pony even if you had an AR-15 to my head, so that left me with writing. I am okay with writing, I can string together a few sentences barely enough to make sense. So here we are…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve read Stephen King’s book ‘On Writing’ on writing. His methodology for creativity is consistency. You write a fixed number of words, everyday, without breaks, and you end up getting better at writing. So I’ve decided to publish something (even if it is only a couple of paragraphs) everyday. I even set up a nice calendar widget to keep track of my writing streaks. Hopefully I’ll have something useful to to write about everyday. Hopefully this exercise will force encourage me to do interesting things in life, like bungee jumping or talking to a homeless person in the subway. Let’s hope so.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                        
                            
                            
                            
                                <category scheme="https://ykumards.github.io/blog/categories/musings/" term="musings" label="musings" />
                            
                        
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
</feed>
