<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-07-09T13:44:21-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title>Yogesh Kumar</title><subtitle>Howdy</subtitle><entry><title>Beginning React</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/beginning-react/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning React" /><published>2016-07-09T11:27:50-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-09T11:27:50-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/beginning-react</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/beginning-react/">&lt;p&gt;React JS took the front-end dev world by storm as soon as &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.github.io/react/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; launched it about 3 years ago. Since then it has grown to become more efficient and powerful. There is a whole ecosystem of React based tools (Redux, React Native, etc…) that it got a bit daunting to get started on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m new to JS web frameworks. I started with Java and then later relied on the simplicity of Python-based frameworks (Flask, you beauty) to get the job done. JS was mostly used for tweaking the responsiveness of the front-end, nothing fancy. Yup, this makes me a dinosaur in today’s world of web development. After some initial skepticism, I understood why the world needs good JS frameworks. Anyway, that was the idea behind getting started with React, because I hear it’s the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone gets started by building this comment box with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.github.io/react/docs/tutorial.html&quot;&gt;official react tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. But after this, things get a bit tricky. I couldn’t really find any resource that would explain the whole React ecosystem well. I’ll try to organise some of what I could understand in the following few posts. Mostly, the material comes from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tylermcginnis33&quot;&gt;Tyler Mcginnis’&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://courses.reactjsprogram.com/courses/reactjsfundamentals&quot;&gt;course&lt;/a&gt;. Do take a look at it if you get a chance, it’s free!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="programming" /><category term="javascript" /><category term="react" /><summary>Getting started with the React JS framework</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;nil}" /></entry><entry><title>Watchmen Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/notes/watchmen-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Watchmen Review" /><published>2016-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/notes/watchmen-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/notes/watchmen-review/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/472331.Watchmen&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 20px&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Watchmen&quot; src=&quot;https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1442239711m/472331.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/472331.Watchmen&quot;&gt;Watchmen&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3961.Alan_Moore&quot;&gt;Alan Moore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1653927115&quot;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Who watches the watchmen?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My first book from the graphic novel genre, and I seemed to have picked up the best. The artwork captivates you from page 1; perfectly portrays the grim darkness of the cold-war era New York city, dingy, drab, filled with an aura of cynicism and the palpable tension from an impending nuclear holocaust. Moore’s characterization of these heroes is intricate, it breaks away from the run-of-the-mill superhero BS of noble ideologies and unicorn sentiments. Here, it’s realistic… grisly – &lt;em&gt;“Existence is random. Has no pattern save what we imagine after staring at it for too long. No meaning save what we choose to impose. This rudderless world is not shaped by vague metaphysical forces”&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;This novel is only a stone’s throw away from being a pure work of psychological realism. Shows why a story about a bunch of superheros needn’t always suck (ahem, Marvel!). 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/44600519-yogesh&quot;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book" /><category term="book-review" /><summary>Who watches the watchmen.</summary></entry><entry><title>The Book Deficit of 2016</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/notes/book-deficit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Book Deficit of 2016" /><published>2016-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/notes/book-deficit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/notes/book-deficit/">&lt;p&gt;I do this ceremoniously every New Year’s day, I open &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/&quot;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt; and sign-up for that year’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/challenges/3890-2016-reading-challenge&quot;&gt;reading challenge&lt;/a&gt;. And if you look at my past record, it’s not been that &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;good&lt;/a&gt;. I start off with a simple idea that I could finish a book a week, which is not that daunting a task when you consider my reading speed :grinning: but I tend to lose track of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year for example, I am behind by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/3853094&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt; books as of now and to complete my goal of 50 books by the end of this year, I have 44 to go in around 6 months! Let me get my excuses out of the way quickly now, this year was busy with all the programming interviews and complex courses (Operating Systems, for example), also I’ve been working on other side projects all along. But that’s no excuse, obviously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go ahead and do the math. I have just over 175 days left to complete 44 books, thats an average of 4 days per book. Not difficult till you consider my programming projects that are currently underway (more on them soon :wink:). However, I think I can squeeze in 2 hours a day for reading books and with that the time I get to finish a book is about 8 hours. That’s not difficult if I pick moderate sized books (Infinite Jest has to wait).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have here a list of books I’ve compiled for this year’s reading list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Things fall apart&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;V for Vendetta&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Quiet American&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany’s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Winner Take Nothing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To the Lighthouse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Me Talk Pretty one Day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To Kill a Mockingbird&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Girl on a Train&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thunderbolt Kid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We Have Always Lived in the Castle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Body in the Library&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creativity Inc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zealot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Writing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cat’s Cradle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1984&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Game of Thrones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Clash of Kings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Mezzanine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My Side of the Mountain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time’s Arrow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Perks of Being a Wallflower&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="book" /><category term="goals" /><summary>Ouch</summary></entry><entry><title>Coding Everyday</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/coding-everyday/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coding Everyday" /><published>2016-07-08T23:52:50-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-08T23:52:50-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/coding-everyday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/coding-everyday/">&lt;p&gt;I came across this post from &lt;a href=&quot;http://ejohn.org/blog/write-code-every-day/&quot;&gt;John Resig&lt;/a&gt; a while back and have been meaning to do this ever since. I have realized that consistency in programming is probably the most important ingredient for improving one’s programming skills. Anyway, I usually get excited about something new, like a programming language or a framework and after playing around with it for a while and then lose touch. It would be better for me if I could organize some of this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already have a few repos on github, and their commit chart should keep me motivated. To obligate myself further, I’ll also write a short note or an elaborate blog post about my work &lt;strong&gt;everyday&lt;/strong&gt;. Of course modifying docs or HTML pages doesn’t count as a commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;topics-to-consider&quot;&gt;Topics to consider&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clojure &amp;amp; Haskell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spotify API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React JS and Native&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaborate on open source projects (&lt;a href=&quot;http://yeoman.io/&quot;&gt;Yeoman&lt;/a&gt; has my attention)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post SICP solved exercise code and notes (I hope to cover a lot of ground this summer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><summary>Code Daily Mahn...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;nil}" /></entry></feed>
